hello everybody and welcome to
geopolitical Trends where truth matters
very excited to be with you because I
have an interesting guest for you and
I'm not going to waste too much time
because my guest is on limited time so
I'm gonna get into it right away so let
me bring in John in here hi John hey how
are you David good to talk to you thank
you very much for being here on car out
time I know how you are and and know so
my my uh my viewers are very excited to
have you here because they gonna be
hearing from your perspective so guys
just regarding John kako bio I put the
entire the full bio in the description
along with the titles of his books so
just for me briefly to give you a heads
up just for you to know who John kako is
is an American Author journalist and a
former CIA intelligence he was also
working in the Senate uh Foreign
Relations Committee in Congress so and
uh he is the the uh host of the
political Misfit along with Michelle
which by the way I'm G to bring in
Michelle next time so FYI guys John
speaks Arabic so just for you to
know
yeah and some of his books guys here is
the latest book here The Reluctant spy
you want you might want to check it out
I have also another picture of the one
of the books here the wi the like of the
wi time like a spy so you might want to
guys take a look at John's books you
will learn a lot because you don't
become a CIA analyst just out of the wh
of those are years and years years of
experience yeah well speaking of that
John I'm going to get into it right away
given your professional background as a
a former CIA analyst as also one who is
dealing with a Foreign Relations
Committee and so forth where do you see
the stage of the global order given the
chaos that's going on what are we
looking at oh I think we are looking at
uh the beginning of a permanent
multi-polar world you know we had this
period from the fall of the Soviet Union
until uh you know until recently until
the last few years where it really was
unipolar with the Chinese making uh some
some moves to the to the front of the
line but I think now we really do have a
unipolar world and I I mean a
multi-polar world yeah yeah and and it
it didn't necessarily have to be from
the American perspective but we made
some strategic errors I think we uh we
pulled out of the jcpoa for example that
was a mistake uh rather than to uh to
work constructively with the Chinese we
decided to well President Obama decided
to Pivot to Asia that was meant to
challenge the Chinese and uh you know
there were so many areas David where we
could have cooperated with the Russians
it it could have been counterterrorism
counternarcotics counter proliferation
all different different areas and we
elected instead to uh to challenge the
Russians now the Russians are not as
economically strong of course as the
Chinese they don't have uh they don't
have the the kind of population that the
Chinese do that will fuel economic
growth but really there are three main
powers in the world right now and
um and uh this is something I think
we're going to have to get used to wow
well speaking of jcpa i as one who wrote
a book about Iran back then I tell Vol
State running the nuclear age and I did
address this issue of the gcpa back then
and I said what is the what if the
possibility of one of the members kind
of withdraw from it or sort of don't
respect the
the the the spirit of the agreements
what I'd like to get your input John is
about the ongoing tensions now between
Israel and Iran and this specifically
pertain to the nuclear aspect do you
foresee in your opinion as of as an
analyst because you have the analytical
thinking do you foresee that Iran will
move into that direction of you know
what the gloves are off we're going to
go ahead for we're going to move forward
with the nuclear device
boy that's a tough one and I I think
well in my heart I think no because
there's no upside for Iran it will open
Iran to any number of attacks and and
lifelong sanctions um but then on the
other side it's probably something that
that the United States and the West
ought to prepare for now again the jcpoa
was a good idea the jcpa work and and
I'll add too that that the the
monitoring mechanism that was called for
in the jcpa was exactly the same
monitoring mechanism that the United
Nations used in Iraq the same lead seals
the same surveillance cameras the same
inspection
regime um and it was working it was
working for for the two or three years
that it was actually in place we decided
to walk away from that um and that's a
shame now now where we ended up burning
ourselves US law says that we have to
impose sanctions on any country that
does business with Iran well as
jcpoa everybody was doing business with
Iran including the British the French
the Germans the Japanese everybody and
so just because Donald Trump decided
that we were going to pull out of the
jcpoa doesn't necessarily mean in our
allies thinking that now they should
pull out of the jcpoa as well or risk
being punished and so the the French
were the first to say to us look if you
want to pull out go ahead and pull out
but we're not pulling out we're signator
to this agreement too and if you want to
sanction us then go ahead and sanction
us and of course we haven't yeah so you
know in the first year or so of the
Biden
Administration it seemed like there was
enough of a desire on the part of the US
government to um to want to re-enter the
jcpa and so we engaged the Iranians in
talks those talks went very poorly uh
not much was was agreed upon and in the
end both sides just uh gave up it was a
bilateral decision we just gave up so
relations are are not good now with that
said I think we underestimate the
Iranians intelligence
in
that I think that they've concluded that
they don't really need a nuclear weapons
program it would be too much of a risk
for them and uh and it would be
incredibly
expensive and uh I I think that if they
really wanted to have a nuclear weapon
they would have it by now they could
have they could have certainly purchased
the the technology from the North
Koreans or from the uh or from the
pakistanis and they haven't done that
very very interesting and now with the
Dynamics that's taking place between
Iran and Israel and as one you spend a
lot of time in the Middle East as matter
of fact you spend a lot of time in Iraq
many years so yeah you so you are you
are very familiar of how the
geopolitical landscape in that part of
the world even back then and now I'm
sure you are witnessing the shift and
the shift that is taking place in light
of what Israel did by attacking the
Iran's Consulate in Damascus and by Iran
retali
do you foresee an open War because a lot
of people are wondering are we going to
be seeing an open war between those two
which means we'll involve other players
no I don't think so and I'll tell you
why um first of all I was stunned by the
Israeli government's very disingenuous
statement yesterday that it never
occurred to them that the that the rest
of the world would consider an attack on
the Iranian consulate as a provocation
like what what what planet do you live
on if if a violation a military
violation of the Vienna convention is
not seen as a provocation so that was
that was for domestic consumption um we
should just ignore it but you know I
have to compliment the Iranians on on
the the great restraint that they have
shown uh really since last October
certainly they are arming the houthis
they're funding and probably arming
Hamas they're arming and financing
Hezbollah in uh in Lebanon leanon uh but
the Israelis have tried repeatedly to
pull the Iranians into this war because
they know that if the Iranians go to war
with Israel the United States will have
to go to war on Israel's side and the
Iranians just have not taken the bait
now God knows they've faced these
provocations uh but look at the Iranian
response last weekend uh you launched
drones and ballistic missiles that take
four hours to reach Israel knowing that
they have the Iron Dome knowing that the
US has Patriot missiles uh in the uh in
the uh region knowing that the
jordanians are also watching the skies
they knew they weren't going to hit
anything but the point was that they
that they responded and they didn't
respond hard enough to make the Israelis
really do something terrible I think it
was a very good decision on the part of
the Iranian government some analysts
were saying that it was a slap on a face
to Israel because Israel now is is not
as of today no decision has been made
within the war cabinet in in in Tel Aviv
whether to retaliate or not that's right
I go I'd like to go back to your point
about the US getting involved with uh
hypothetically we go with the
hypothetical here should this go forward
with an open War what do do you think
Russia and China will do viav supporting
Iran will they move forward with that or
not that's a that's a very good question
you know just uh last week
um and I don't even remember now who it
was it it may have been the Polish the
Polish president suggested almost
offhandedly that maybe the Chinese would
be interested in mediating and then
within 48 Hours the Chinese were
offering to mediate so you know one
thing about China
I I'm not I'm not a fan of the Chinese
government of course but uh but the
Chinese do not W with with very specific
exceptions the Chinese do not have a
history of um imperialism you know they
took Tibet absolutely they took it
they've held it ever since they have
fought Border Wars with the Indians they
have fought Border Wars with the
Vietnamese but but they don't go around
the world invading other countries or
attacking under other countries it's
just not something that's a part of
their foreign policy so I can't I can't
see the Chinese being becoming directly
involved in a Middle East conflict I do
believe that the Chinese will offer to
mediate the Russians absent a conflict
in
Ukraine um would have to come in on the
side of the Palestinians not militarily
necessarily yeah but I think with with
weapons and with
um and with assistance and material and
ammunition and and things like that
although you know you're talking about a
lot of nuclear uh nuclear countries here
and I I just like to I just like to
believe
that that cooler heads in a situation
like that would Prevail yeah yeah but at
the same time the West is preventing
anything from moving forward if I just
uh can uh uh uh uh mentioned when China
wanted to offer to mediate between
Russia and Ukraine what did we do yeah
we Ste forward and kind of shut the door
on that because we saw the success that
China achieved when it comes down to
establishing diplomatic ties between
irania yeah two AR so I do see the
possibility of something like this but
the West is gonna I think the statement
by the Polish president was nothing but
for domestic consumptions also because
they don't want to see uh the Ukrainian
conflicts resolved which by the way you
and I know there is no way out but
negotiation yes and I'd like to have you
I'd like to have your input on that that
that's a point that I try to make as
often as possible and I and I I say it
frequently in in my writing one thing
that the United States has been bad at
in the last 20 years is allowing the
diplomats to do their job I I remember
when I was still at the CIA we
complained all the time about the the
George W Bush Administration because I
had never seen an Administration works
so hard to not talk to our enemies as
the as the George W Bush Administration
going back going back to well I was
going to say the Nixon Administration
but you could go all the way back to the
end of the second world war and
engagement with the Soviet Union for
example and then beginning with with uh
Nixon engagement with both the Soviet
Union and China was was a Mainstay of
American foreign policy George W bush
made a decision to not engage with our
enemies and that's become policy for
both of the major political parties here
in the United States that's a that's a a
mistake and you know we we used to say
we used to say that here in the United
States our own partisan differences
ended at the shore right and overseas we
were always
unified well you know what now we're
unified again but in the wrong way in in
a bad way we're unified in that we have
this foreign policy where we try not to
engage with the governments of countries
with which we disagree and I think
that's just a terrible mistake I I'll
add one other thing too if you don't
mind sure I had I had occasion to um to
speak with the Russian ambassador to uh
the United States several months ago I
had written a column that he had read
and one of his AIDS reached out and he
invited me to lunch the the Ambassador
invited me to lunch and so he said he
wanted to know one thing even in this
time of war is there any way that the
United States and Russia can cooperate
on something and I said oh yes and I've
been consistent with this I said
look Afghanistan produces 93% of the
world's heroin almost all of that heroin
goes to Russia and Iran and Russia and
Iran have the highest rates of opioid
Addiction in the world five times the
rate of opioid addiction that we have
here in the United States so we can
absolutely cooperate on counter uh
narcotics which we don't do um we are
just as worried as the Russians are
about uh the prospect of terrorist
groups or Rogue Nations acquiring file
material so we should be and could be
cooperating on counter proliferation and
Russia has been the victim of terrorism
just like the United States has been a
victim of terrorism and so we should be
cooperating on counterterrorism there
was a piece in the Washington Post just
today saying that Tajikistan as small as
it is and as small a population as it
has provides more fighters to Isis on a
per capita basis than any other country
in the world we should be cooperating
with the Russians on that to stop that
and and you do that by by encouraging
Economic Development and education but
very very we're working with them yeah
yeah uh let me go back to the Middle
East because again there's a lot
anything happen on a global stage if the
Middle East is involved you know how it
is it's gonna like suck in all the
energy from what I wanted to get your
input on is the role of the Arab and
Muslim countries hypothetically should
an open War escalate what do you
anticipate what do you see because I see
now Jordan is already Egypt I can't
trust them the Turks are playing both
sides I look at Turks with the issue of
Cyprus and and Greek you know that that
story then so Saudis and United Arab
Emirates you know they giving a lip
service to Americans but they do win
their T behind the scenes where do you
see the role of the Muslim world that is
wishiwashi as far as what he stands on
that's a good way of putting it
um and I would have to agree with you I
think it's largely
wishy-washy you know looking at these
countries independently of one another
the Saudis regardless of their new
relations with the Iranians the Saudis
hate the Iranians and they fear them the
bahrainis fear them and hate them even
more than the Saudis do the kuwaitis
want to just be left alone the emiratis
prefer strong business ties to to Israel
but they're willing to take a step back
over the course of this uh this conflict
the gries are pro Hamas period they
always have been um the omanis are the
diplomats of the peninsula so they want
everybody just to get along uh but then
you look at the Egyptians the Turks uh
you know some of these other countries
the jordanians as you pointed out the
jordanians you know are are in the world
um are are in the the wrong neighborhood
is what I meant to say
yeah they worry about the Israelis
because they share such a long border
with Israel but at the same time fully
50% of Jordan's population is
Palestinian Palestinian and so they have
to stand up for the Palestinians
Palestinian rights and Palestinian human
rights yeah um the syrians it goes
without saying uh are are constantly uh
wronged uh wronged by the Israelis so um
you know it comes down to the Egyptians
and and what have the Egyptians done
since October 7th the Egyptians have
done really nothing to help the
Palestinians they've sealed the Border
because what's what's the thing that the
Egyptians want the least they want an
open border where Palestinians are going
to stream across it and have to be
placed in refugee camps uh in Sinai
that's happened before they don't want
it to happen again okay so I think that
the bottom line here David is that all
of these Arab countries are taking this
this unfortunate weight and see attitude
thinking um what position can I take
that is going to cause the least amount
of damage to my own country and then
their thoughts of the Palestinians are
secondary to that very very interesting
let's shift to and I know given the
timing and I'm keeping an eye on it uh
let's shift to Ukraine Russia conflict
and the reason I wanted to uh tackle
this before we go to Far East in Asia
we'll close up with that so uh for the
Ukraine Russia conflict what do you
anticipate Mo coming forward given the
statement last week by the Secretary of
State Anthony BL saying that well of
course we're gonna admit Ukraine to Nato
which was crazy statement anyway I don't
even know why he said that uh what I
wanted to get your input John on is the
idea that Russia is moving forward with
some plan yeah are we seeing Russia
taking over Kiev anytime soon I don't
think so um you know the Russians the
Russians from from very shortly after
the start of the War uh have been
suggesting uh uh peace talks right that
would that would be brokered either by
the Chinese or by the Turks um the
United States and Ukraine have rejected
that from the very beginning now the
conventional wisdom is that the
ukrainians just cannot maintain this
pace of War they just can't they can't
hold the territory that they reclaimed
from the Russians the Russians are
moving back in good weather is upon us
and that makes it easier for the
Russians to move west the bigger problem
is that the Republican party here in the
United States has turned on Ukraine
whether it's for ideological reasons or
for economic reasons the Republicans
just don't want to fund this thing
anymore now on Saturday the House of
Representatives is going to vote to
provide another $61 billion in Aid to
Ukraine half of that is going to um is
going to be in the form of a loan
a loan that would be forgiven after the
election so um how much longer are we
gonna are we going to end up uh doing
that I think that there's really no
National there's no National desire
anymore here in the United States to
keep funding this this war and providing
material for this war and at the same
time Russia is so much bigger and so
much stronger than Ukraine the
ukrainians just don't have the
population to keep this thing going uh
forever
wow yeah and I think Ukrainian just did
the crossed one of the red lines now by
attacking I think a radar system that
deals with the nuclear weapons for
Russia which is a red line for I wonder
how uh the Russian president is gonna
respond to this but but it would be
interesting to see yeah now if we are to
think about this will Europe ever take a
a stand as far as pushing back against
the us as far as you know we're done
with this let's sit down done with the
Russians and negotiate a settlement do
you see the Europeans taking an
initiative like
this not under a Democratic president no
now if Donald Trump becomes president
again he's expressed such anti-nato
sentiment that I think the Europeans
would want to take leadership of of NATO
so long as there's a democrat in the
white house or a republican who's not
named Donald Trump
um then I think I think that NATO is
going to continue to look to the United
States for leadership and for the bulk
of the NATO budget um at the same time
you know you've got to ask yourself if
if NATO is really still necessary yeah I
I'm I personally believe that it's that
it's not you know I I learned something
interesting the other
day um what is the only time in the
history of NATO starting in 1948 to the
present where NATO was called upon to
defend another NATO country from Attack
do you know it was it was September 11th
11th yeah that was it that was it and
NATO came to our defense now
unfortunately that meant going to
Afghanistan to occupy
Afghanistan but um but that's the only
time and you know and another thing too
is it really worth the effort and the
money we have promised promised the
Russians repeatedly over the course of
the last four
presidents that we would not continue to
expand NATO to Russia's borders and then
we've broken that promise repeatedly
look at lvia Lithuania
Estonia Poland uh you know we just keep
doing it over and over and over again
and we we give the Russians no reason to
uh to trust us trust us yeah yeah we
lost credibility I mean I've I've been
saying this even during my time in
Washington that I was in a thick of it
in a sense of what are we doing here and
sometimes you know you'll have a
conversation with the boss that the boss
will invite you for dinner just to pick
your brain or stuff and I say sir that's
where this is going is not going to B
well for us interest in the long term
and of course you know you get the
bureaucracy over there and all that
stuff so uh let me shift to just for my
viewers guys uh for just prepare a
question or two uh for John later on
before before I I let him go here so may
I may I anticipate a question or pre a
question sure sure let me if I see one
here forgive me if if this is
embarrassing to you but I feel compelled
to say something because I'm I'm
glancing at the chat yeah let me see
because I wasn't looking at it at all
I'll see a question here yeah go ahead
John if you think that I am still in the
CIA after I blew the whistle on the
cia's torture program lost my pension
lost my job lost my family lost my
freedom for two years and you think I'm
still in the CIA that is the epitome of
intellectual
laziness sorry yeah there it is no
you're right I didn't see that one and I
guys I know I well I do have a I do have
the community here John be are very very
respectful very intellectual sometimes
I'll get to those trolls and so forth
and uh so I'm glad you said something so
I didn't see it and I will check out all
this later on after that so let's talk
about the uh uh let's talk about uh Far
East China yeah and the reason I want to
get your input on this because it just
came to my attention this morning
believe it or not that the Philippines
and the US is is gonna be conducting
Naval drills yeah but not not this is
the key not on the Filipino Waters yes
so this is crazy right yeah well what
does it mean John how do you how do you
explain this you know it's this it's
this unnecessarily provocative pivot to
Asia that that started with Barack Obama
um listen we we have a very very long
relationship with the Filipino
government it's had its ups and downs we
used the biggest Air Force Base in the
world there uh Clark Air Force Base we
used to have the biggest naval base in
the world there Subic Bay we don't
anymore but now uh we have um we've
moved much more closely toward the the
Filipinos and vice versa in the last 10
years uh or so and then just last week
we had the Japanese prime minister here
in Washington for a state dinner and the
very next day uh the the president of uh
the Philippines bung Bang Marcos he came
as well for this trilateral meeting the
meeting was all about confronting China
the whole thing was about confronting
China not about protecting the
Philippines not about protecting Japan
but about being proactively provocative
against the uh the Chinese one of the
things that I think many American policy
makers
forget is that it was the Chinese who
were attacked by the Japanese and and
the the the
viciousness of that attack which lasted
from the 1930s into the middle of the
1940s it's a part of the Chinese DNA you
know Chinese children are taught about
the the viciousness of the the Japanese
Occupation it's the Chinese that are
more worried about what the Japanese
might do to them than the
reverse and so why we've decided to
confront the Chinese like this
in the South China Sea of all places or
in the straights of Taiwan or or on a on
an island that's only six miles off the
coast of of mainland China by by putting
a thousand US troops I just don't get
what the end game is yeah well I still
thinking the idea that some in
Washington still looking at Philippines
as a colony for us you know doesn't
matter sovereignty or not it's just on a
paper there is a SE there is another
point that I was aware of and this has
to do with the current president Marcus
Jr Bono's father's assets that been sort
of blocked in the US could it this be a
part of that because I was aware of what
F Ferdinand Marcos senior assets were at
that time were blocked
yeah you and I are of a certain age
exactly in terms of of foreign uh policy
I I was a senior in college when first n
Marcus was overthrown in the People
Power movement it was very very powerful
and um and you're right that whole
family was under sanctions I remember
that uh Elda had something like what was
it 10,000 20,000 pairs of shoes crazy
thing you know while while people were
living in poverty and squalor in her
country how in the world that family
came back I have no idea but I think
you're right David I I think that at
least the families assets are are frozen
been confiscated and turned back over to
the Filipino people I would assume yeah
but it's just my concern with rushing up
tensions in that part of the world
especially when you consider that NATO
wanted to open an office in Tokyo yeah
and you kind of start to wonder why are
we going to the Far East to create more
tensions over there what for yeah and in
fact in fact we gave Japan um uh major
non-nato status that's an actual status
with capital letters major non-nato Ally
status Saudi Arabia is a major non-nato
Ally Bahrain is a non a major non-nato
Ally my guess is the Philippines is
going to get it right soon oh what does
it mean like we have now access to yeah
they have access to to some weapons and
weapon systems that they otherwise
wouldn't have access to for example the
UAE Australia uh Saudi Arabia they have
access to the F35 so we'll give the 3 to
the Japanese as well and and we don't
for other countries in fact turkey is a
member of NATO and we won't give them
the
F35 wow yeah wow well that explains it
now why Japan went ahead and increased
its defense budget for 20124 oh yeah
because because we order them to you
know the the guideline for NATO is that
you have to spend at least two% of your
GDP on uh on a military budget and
something like three or four countries
um spend that much money on on three or
four NATO countries spend that much
money on uh on their defense budgets but
we're demanding it and we're we're
forcing them to spend more money it's
it's very dangerous very very
interesting I want to take one last
topic with you briefly here and this has
to do with turkey and Greece or Cyprus
is something you are very very very
familiar with uh given your background
given also part of your professional
career been spent in that part of the
world so why what what do you think of
turkey sort of will it be will there be
a war or a conflict I won't use the term
war between Greece and and and turkey
when turkey agitate that country I I
gave an interview to a Greek newspaper
uh a few days ago and they asked me
exactly exactly the same question and I
think no I I think there's no chance of
a of a conflict there's there's very
disturbing rhetoric going back and forth
I I'll say that and you know when the
Turkish Defense Minister says that
turkey has a plan to take all of
Greece's aian Islands in 48 48 hours or
that turkey has a strategic plan to
launch ballistic missiles on Athens
which of course is a population Center
you have to take those kinds of threats
seriously but the Turks always talk like
that and very rarely do they come close
to actual shooting the last time they
came close to to the actual exchange of
gunfire was during the Clinton
Administration and it was over an an
iset called emia which doesn't even have
people on it it has only a herd of goats
and wow it's a Greek island but the
Turks put the Turkish flag then the
Greek uh Coast Guard went they took it
down they put a Greek flag and you know
then their ships went and Bill Clinton
had to call both sides and tell them to
cut it out so I I think a lot of this is
is just rhetoric now more importantly
mhm
is vast amounts of natural gas have been
found off the Southeastern coast of
Cyprus stretching to Lebanon um Israel
and Palestine and um and the Israelis
the cypriotes the Greeks and American
oil companies have
begun exploring testing and lifting some
of that gas the Turks Fe feel cut out
and although none of that
gas as has been discovered yet is in
Turkish territorial Waters I think
probably a wise thing to do might be to
share some of the wealth with the Turks
and keep everybody happy as things stand
right
now um the Turks recently sent a a
battleship to confront a French uh oil
exploration ship
and so there's there's very little going
on in in the way of uh of exploration
right now this is a problem also for the
for the Israelis and the Palestinians
because much of that field is accessible
from from Gaza from Palestine and you
know in the original agreement between
all these different countries there was
an
acknowledgment that that Palestine and
they use they use the word Palestine or
Palestinians is what it is that
Palestinians own some of this gas but
that it would be up to the Israeli
government to decide how much of the
money the Palestinians get and you know
what the answer is going to be it's
going to be zero yeah so we'll see yeah
it's this
is all right let me take a guys because
John is on limited time he was kind
enough just to car out this time for us
here I'll have him back on the show
don't worry I'm going to take one
question or two just to be respectful of
his time uh army with Harmony this is an
avid supporter of the channel John so
question my understanding is that the
Golan height was hit and the Air Force
Base was damaged when Israel when Israel
retaliates will Iran continue to
generally Target military assets only
that's that's a very good question I saw
the same reports that that it was Golan
that was hit and I also saw a report
that one rocket got through and and hit
the edge of an Israeli base north of aot
so you know this this again goes to goes
to the
um goes to the very patient policy of
the Iranian government on this thing I
mean they could have they could have
targeted Tel Aviv you know and and
civilian population centers like the
Israelis have frankly yeah and and they
didn't do that and so my guess is that
if there is going to be more Iranian
targeting it's going to be of Israeli
military facilities I think that's
actually a wise policy and you want to
know my my uh my my thoughts about it i'
love to hear that why R didn't is
because when Bill Burns CIA director
went to Oman that's when he asked
directly the Iranians yes just do
something but avoid the civilians that's
why the Iranians I think but they will
be know next time there will be no next
time for Iran make my word on it guys if
Israel conducts some crazy stuff Iran's
gonna upstage the game by using its
Advanced missiles and we all know what
it means so uh I want to say thank you
here to Francis Tango thank you for your
super sticker and he's saying thank you
to you John also for the information
thanks very much very very I have a
wonderful uh group here uh that they
share the information intelligently and
and uh respectful and timeline Dunley
one last question here uh uh to Dr o do
you hear anything about China making the
energy force feel chill do you know
anything about that John no that's the
first I've heard of it that's first time
I heard of it too I I need to look into
this like like an Iron Dome idea uh I I
don't know I don't know I'm going to
look into this and check it out because
I do know China is working on something
very very highly Advanced uh but it's
not here it's on the surface of the
Moon that I'm aware of but I I'll check
on this one here well John I can thank
you enough for really really really your
time where can my viewers find you and
find your work and so for ah thank you I
publish everything I do on substack it's
at John kiraku and I'm also on Twitter
at John Kaku okay I'm going to post
those for you guys on the description
just check it out there I do follow John
on on Twitter just go ahead and follow
him on Twitter as well and read up his
article on the substack so once again
thank you so much John truly appreciate
you and I look forward to next time I'm
looking forward to
it all right guys I hope you find this
very informative I know John is on was
on limited time because he has other
stuff it was just kind as I said kind
enough to carve out this time for us
here for you to hear a different
perspective there is the reason why I
also wanted to reach reach out to John
because someone I trust someone has been
inside understand the system understand
the global stage knows how to read the
geopolitical landscape and I just want
you have the opportunity to listen to a
different perspective as always remember
geopolitics impact your daily life in
more ways than one till next time guys
bye-bye